

UX Designer/Developer

My passion is **cross-discipline collaboration** that results in **functional design**, **improvement in a human's experience** of a product or service, and **increases in meaningful business metrics.** I can design, develop, and/or manage teams.

timdose@gmail.com 917-575-5359 timdose.com/ux

Work Experience

Yodle

2012-Present

User Experience Manager

- Led user testing and A/B testing on Yodle.com which has raised web conversion 30%.
- Led the re-design and development of Yodle's newest CMS, powering over 10,000 of Yodle's client sites. Led to a 17% increase in client satisfaction and a 60% improvement in setup time.
- Conducted A/B tests on Yodle's customers' sites which improved conversion 10%.
- Pioneered Lean processes in conjuction with the Marketing team.
- Managed and mentored Interaction Designers, Visual Designers, and Front End Developers.

2012 Lead UX Front Developer

- Led the design and development for over 100 templates for Yodle's previous CMS.
- Collaborated with Marketing Ops to run Yodle's first A/B test which **increased conversion 9**% on Yodle's customers' sites.
- Prioritized template coverage needs based on sales velocity.

2011-2012 UX Front End Developer

- Increased template quality and development speed by standardizing design and dev processes.
- Designed and developed dozens of web templates.

2010-2011 Web Designer/Developer

- Created client sites and pioneered design/development techniques on newly built in-house CMS.
- Trained and supported Client Service Reps on in-house CMS.
- Mentored and trained fellow developers in best practices, including JavaScript and Firebug.

Freelance

2003-2010

Web Designer/Developer

- Designed and developed user-customizable websites for artists and writers.
- $\bullet \ \, \text{Designed and built lightweight CMS for clients to upload, edit, and maintain their own content.}$

Rebel Monkey Games

2007-2009

Lead Game Artist/Technical Artist

- Created 2D and 3D character and background art for Flash-based multiplayer casual games.
- Designed, developed, and illustrated an animated avatar system for users to customize their ingame characters along 20+ parameters.
- \bullet Created the front end for the game's virtual clothing store.
- Worked closely with engineers and the other artists to create pipelines for game assets.

Lindgren & Smith, Inc.

2001-2007

IT Specialist

- Developed and maintained multiple company websites.
- Created custom database solution to track clients, projects, and invoices.
- Built asset management database to catalog thousands of images by 40+ artists.

About

Skills

- User Research
- · Interaction Design
- · Web Development
- · Project Management
- Team Management

Methodologies & Processes

- Agile UX, Lean UX
- · Usability Testing
- A/B Testing
- Information Architecture
- · Process Flows, Wireframing
- · Personas, Card Sorting
- · Responsive Design
- Continuous Integration
- Test-Driven Development
- · Unit Testing, E2E Testing

Technologies

- HTML/HTML5
- CSS/CSS3, LESS
- · Javascript, PHP, Python
- ¡Query, Bootstrap, AngularJS
- ExpressJS, CherryPy
- Nunjucks, Jinja, Jade
- MySQL, PostgreSQL
- Mocha, Chai, Supertest
- · Webdriver, Selenium
- Git, Mercurial, SVN
- Heroku, Amazon Elastic Beanstalk

Tools

- Adobe Creative Suite
- OmniGraffle
- Optimizely, Mouseflow, Google Analytics
- Jira, Trello
- Maya, 3ds Max, Blender, zBrush

Education

 BFA in Illustration, Syracuse University